EMMANUEL IKEKWERE

(512) 351 5297 | emmaikekwere@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/ikekwere-emmanuel/ Austin, TX

DATA ANALYST

2+ years of experience streamlining IT systems and data analytics processes to increase efficiency, productivity, accuracy, and revenue. Improved customer satisfaction ratings by 25%, increased user satisfaction, improved uptime by 50%, and scaled productivity by 95%.

WORK EXPERIENCE

STUDENT CONSULTANT - IT ANALYST - A-I Health - Austin, TX

September 2022 - Present

- Led the implementation of a data-driven solution resulting in a 20% increase in efficiency in 3 months.
- Improved IT system uptime by 20% in 2months, leading to increased customer satisfaction.
- Developed cross-functional management skills in driving clients' outcomes and creating best practice through thought leadership and collaboration.

DATA AND RESEARCH ANALYST - C7 Technologies - Calabar, Nigeria

February 2019 - July 2022

- Increased sales by 30% in 6 months through product pricing optimization and strategic marketing initiatives.
- In 3 months, led the data-driven research resulting in increased efficiency of 20% operational excellence.
- Implemented cost optimization and increased project completion rate by 30% in 8 months.

ASSOCIATE PROJECT ANALYST - CLATURE PROJECTS - Lagos, Nigeria

February 2016 - January 2019

- Reduced overall project costs by \$45,000 in 12 months by streamlining processes and utilizing resources more efficiently.
- Achieved a 33% reduction in data processing time by implementing innovative data analysis techniques in 60 days, utilizing SQL.

EDUCATION

MASTER OF SCIENCE IN ANALYTICS – Harrisburg University of Science and Technology, Pennsylvania Relevant Courses: Data Visualization, Exploratory Data Analysis, Application of Machine Learning, Data Analytics

October 2024

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE, APPLIED MATHEMATICS – Federal University of Agriculture, Nigeria **November 2015 Relevant Courses:** Operations Research, Time Series Analysis, Database Management, Data Mining, Predictive Analysis

SKILLS

- Programming Languages: R, PostgreSQL, Python, AWS, CSS, SAS, JavaScript, HTML, Bootstrap.
- Data Visualization: Power BI, Tableau, R Studio, Matplotlib.
- Others: Microsoft Excel, Git, Visual Studio, Agile Methodologies.
- Strong Communication and Interpersonal, Presentation, Problem solving, Decision Making, Time Management.

PROJECTS

PRICE ANALYSIS OF AIRBNB RENTALS IN SEATTLE, WASHINGTON

February 2023

- Analyze 5000+ rental listings using problem-solving skills to determine impact on rental price.
- Performed data cleaning and analysis to understand and recommend effective pricing strategies for Airbnb users.
- Led the project team in analyzing data to effectively communicate the correlation between reviews and rental prices under \$200.

STATION LOCATION AND TRIPS ANALYSIS ON INDEGO BIKE STATION, PENNSYLVANIA

February 2023

- Transformed and filtered data to treat anomalies and improve data reporting process.
- Performed data screening using exploratory data analysis framework and predictive analysis for 250,000+ bike trips data.
- Applied linear regression and data visualization techniques to understand predictors in the final regression model.

MEMBERSHIP